迈克:好的,国王正在盘算,他靠着,
Mike: Alright, the king is mean.The king is lean.He's shooting.Here he goes.
投篮,他进了,命中了三分……
He's up to three...
波纳:迈克,现在是凌晨4点,我们还没学完呢?
Boner: Mikey.It's four am.Any time to get some studying done?
迈克:放松点,这又不是最后一星期.
Mike: Relax.You are acting like this is finals week.
波纳:它是.
Boner: It is.
迈克:是的!118,
Mike: Yes!One hundred and eighteen.In a row.
他能够连续创造119的纪录吗?
Can he go for a record one hundred and nineteen?
波纳:迈克,我想我更需要学习,而不是破纪录.
Boner: Mikey, I think I need to study more than you need that record.
迈克:波纳,放松点.我们还有整整5个小时,准备历史期末考试足够了.
Mike: Boner relax.We've got a whole five hours.There's plenty of time to practice
for this history final
波纳:是科学期末考试.
Boner: Science final.
迈克:管他什么呢,别紧张.
Mike: Whatever.Come on.Don't be so tense.
波纳:迈克,我一直在想.
Boner: Mikey, I've been doing some thinking.
迈克:如果你这样做很危险,波纳,
Mike: A very dangerous thing for you to be doing Boner.
尤其是在期末考试的星期里.
Especially during final's week.
波纳:我一直在问自己某些问题.
Boner: I've been asking myself certain questions.
迈克:嘿,如果不是选择题,我可猜不出
Mike: Hey, if they are not multiple choice, you aint got a shot.
波纳:迈克,不,不……
Boner: Mikey no, no...
迈克:嘿,波纳.
Mike: Hey Bone.Just look at yourself.
看看你自己,你看上去只有三尺高,
You look like you are three feet tall with your legs growing out of your
腿从胳膊下面长出来.好了,
armpits.Alright alright, we'll study.
好了,我们要学习,我讨厌一个满脸悲观的矮子.
I hate to see a dwarf with a bad attitude.I mean come on.
我是说开始吧,振作起来,
Cheer up Bone.Remember the school's policy;
波纳.记住学校的政策,
First semester freshmen can not flunk out.
第一个学期的新生是不能因为考试不及格而退学的,就算他们的成绩和我们一样的恶心.
Even if their grades are as lousy as ours.
波纳:你总算严肃一点了,
Boner: Well now that you are in serious mode,
我可以和你谈谈吗?
can I talk to you about something?Come here.
迈克:当然,让我先舒服点.讲吧!
Mike: Sure, let me get comfortable here.Speak!
波纳:好的,这想法像个像皮球一样一直在我的脑袋里蹦来蹦去.
Boner: Ok, this thought has been bouncing around my head like a rubber ball.
我们像现在这样,大学肯定毕不了业.
We can't go through college, the way we've been doing, for much longer.
我是说,我们不再是高中生了.
I mean, we aint High School anymore.Things are changing.
情况不同了,我可以留胡子,
I can grow facial hair.
现在我在考虑让我的生活发生一些大的,很大的变化.
Now I've been thinking about making some big, big changes in my life.
你有没有觉得这样只是在虚度?(迈克打呼噜声)也许不是.
Do you ever feel that just getting by is getting old?(Mike snoring) Guess not!
(一星期以后)(发成绩单的日子)
(A Week Later) (The Day the Grades Arrive)
朱莉:本,你有信.
Julie: Ben, you got some mail.
本:谁来的?
Ben: From who?
朱莉:爱德?迈克曼.
Julie: Ed MacMan.
本:我没听说过.
Ben: Never heard of him.
迈克:嘿,本,有人送信来了?
Mike: Hey Ben, has anyone brought the mail in yet?
本:(吞吞吐吐,嘴里吃着东西)
Ben: (speaking with food in his mouth)
迈克:你就不能别把它塞进嘴里?
Mike: Would you take that thing out of your mouth.
本:那样我怎么吃吗
Ben: Well how else am I supposed to eat it?
迈克:你知道?我带赶在爸妈之前看.
Mike: Look, do you know?I got to look through it before mum and dad do.
本:他们刚拿了.
Ben: They just got it.
迈克:你给了他们?你怎么能这样对我,你这个小兔崽子?
Mike: What did you give it to them?How could you do that to me
you little doof
朱莉:这儿发生什么了?
Julie: What's going on in here?
本:是迈克,他发疯了,关于这封邮件.
Ben: It's Mike.He's gone crazy.It's about the mail.
朱莉:我刚给你父母拿过去,里面有你的信.
Julie: I just brought it into your parents.There was something for you.
本:你惹麻烦了,朱莉.
Ben: You're in big trouble.Julie.
迈克:谢谢你,朱莉.
Mike: Well thank you.Julie.
你做了这些真好.
That was just so sweet of you to go out of your way like that.
本:他为什么对你这么好?你身上哪些东西我没有呢?
Ben: Why is he so nice to you?What have you got that I haven't got?
迈克:嘿,早上好,爸爸妈妈.在看邮件呢.
Mike: Hey, good morning mum and dad.Looking through the mail I see.
杰森:你在等新的一期吧?
Jason: Expecting your new issue of "Boy's Life"?
迈克:不是.
Mike: No.
杰森:是这封来自阿尔夫?兰登初级学院的信吗?
Jason: Well how about this letter from the Alf Landen Junior College?
麦琪:注册办公室.
Maggie: Office of the registrar.
迈克:嘿,你们知道,我的注册员老朋友.
Mike: Hey what so you know.My old pal the registrar.
麦琪:成绩单吧,迈克?
Maggie: Midsemester grades Mike?
迈克:嘿,妈妈,
Mike: Hey mum.No need to assume that.
不需要假设.嘿,你知道瑞吉他在信里什么都可能写.
Hey, you know Reggie here could be writing about almost anything.
杰森:啊,
Jason: Ah Mike, Boner called."
迈克,波纳打电话说"有坏消息时来我家,
Come over to my house when you get your bad news"."
我们可以一起打开".
We can open them together".
迈克:哦,谢谢.
Mike: Oh, thanks.
开萝尔:如果那些是迈克的成绩,你们为什么不打开呢?
Carol: If those are Mike's grades, how come you didn't open them?
杰森:开萝尔,这信不是寄给我们的.
Jason: Carol, the letter was not addressed to us.
你哥哥有隐私权.
Your brother has his right to privacy.
开萝尔:你们把信放在灯下看.
Carol: Well you could have just held the envelope up to the light.
麦琪和杰森:是的,可是信封太厚了.
Maggie and Jason: Yeah, the paper was too thick.
迈克:好的,你准备好了吗?
Mike: Alright, you ready?
波纳:准备好了.
Boner: I'm ready.
迈克:准备哭吧.等等,等等!你打开我的,我打开你的.
Mike: Read em and weep.Wait, wait!You open mine and I'll open yours.
波纳:为什么?
Boner: Why?
迈克:从朋友那得到坏消息总是要好些.
Mike: It's always better to get bad new from a friend.
迈克:我怎么样?
Mike: How did I do?
波纳:你真幸运,逃过一劫了,全是D.
Boner: You lucky son of a gun.You aced it.All D's.
迈克:太好了!西维尔过了.
Mike: Alright!He he!The Seaver gets by.
波纳:我怎么样?
Boner: So, how did I do?
迈克:说实话?
Mike: The truth?
波纳:都是F?
Boner: Bunch of F's hu?
迈克:嘿,别难过,
Mike: Hey look, now don't get all upset and freak out like you always
波纳,事情很快就会过去,就像以前一样.
do Boner.This will just blow over like it always does.
波纳:我早知道会这样,这叫做第六感觉.
Boner: I knew this was going to happen.Call it extra sensory reception.
迈克:波纳,你去哪?
Mike: Boner, where are you going?
波纳:我要去告诉爸爸.
Boner: I got to tell my parents what happened.
迈克:你想什么呢?听着,
Mike: What are you thinking here man?
你这是自投罗网,来,
Listen, that's like walking into an ambush.
我们去看电影吧.
I mean, come on, let's go see a movie or something.
你需要时间来忘记这事.如果你想要哭,
You need some time to snap out of this.If you need to cry, go ahead.
你就哭吧,我走开.
I'll look away.
波纳:迈克我感觉很好,事实上,我感觉以刚才好多了.
Boner: Mike I'm feeling fine.In fact I'm feeling better by the minute.
Mike: What do you mean you feel better?Come on, you got a bunch of
F's
你不为此难为情?
Not that that's anything to be ashamed of.
波纳:该是换个角度了想想了.
Boner: It's time to see things in a different light now.
迈克:波纳,你在这儿做什么?
Mike: Bone, what's going on here?
波纳:有时候男人必须要做男人该做的事.
Boner: Sometimes a man's got to do what a man's got to do.
杰森:我还是那样想,麦琪,
Jason: I still want to offer the thought, Maggie,
迈克成绩很糟,可我们还不知道.
that we don't know for a fact that Mike's grades were bad.
麦琪:哦,宝贝,当你愚蠢幼稚的时候,看起来真可爱.
Maggie: Oh honey, you look so cute when you are being foolish and naive.
杰森:我知道,我是很幼稚.
Jason: I know.I mean about being naive.
麦琪:迈克什么时候才能考虑一下将来呢?
Maggie: When's Mike going to wake up and smell the future?
杰森:那是我的梦想,某一天某件事能够触动他.也许他会听见"是时候了,
Jason: Well it's my dream that someday something's going to hit him.
迈克,是时候了".还是很可爱吗?
Maybe he'll hear voices say "It's time Mike, it's time".Looking cute again?
麦琪:很可爱.杰森,
Maggie: Adorable.Still Jason, we can't ignore this.
我们还不能不管,我们必须让他知道我们很失望.
We have to let him know that we are disappointed.
杰森:我同意,但是我不想对他大喊大叫.
Jason: I agree, but I don't think it would do any good yelling at him.
麦琪:好的,我同意.
Maggie: Well I agree.
杰森:嘿,迈克,你好吗?
Jason: Hey Mike.How are you doing?
麦琪:你饿吗?
Maggie: You hungry?
迈克:妈妈,爸爸,我知道你们在这想什么,
Mike: Mum, dad, I know what you are both thinking here,
所以我不想瞒你们.妈妈,
so I won't keep you in suspense.Now mum, you were right.
你是对的,今天我收到的信就是我的成绩单.你能给我盐吗?
That letter I got in the mail today, was my grades.Can you pass the salt?
麦琪:还有呢?
Maggie: And?
迈克:胡椒.
Mike: The pepper.
麦琪:还有呢?
Maggie: And?
迈克:请吧.
Mike: Please.
开萝尔:本和我应该待在楼上,直到你们对着迈克吼叫完吗?
Carol: Should Ben and I wait upstairs until you are done yelling at Mike?
杰森:不用.
Jason: No.
开萝尔:过来,本.我们可以看看.
Carol: Come on in Ben.We get to watch.
杰森:没有大吼大叫.
Jason: There's not going to be any yelling.
本:有吃的吗?
Ben: Is there going to be any food?
杰森:有.
Jason: Yes.
本:那我就待着.
Ben: I'll stay.
麦琪:过来,迈克,以成人对成人的方式.你可以告诉我们你的成绩,
Maggie: Come on Mike.Adult to adult.You can tell us what your grades were.
不用担心,像你爸爸说的,没人会训斥你,我们保证.
And don't worry, like your father said, there will be no yelling.We promise.
迈克:我……
Mike: I....
本:I!你得了一个I!那比F还糟.
Ben: I!You got an I!That's worse than an F.
迈克:实话告诉你们,我得的全是D.
Mike: For your information I got all D's.
杰森:全是D!全是D,你很高兴……嗯.
Jason: All D's!All D's, and you're happ....uh hu.
麦琪:迈克,我不知道说什么.
Maggie: Mike, I don't know what to say.
开萝尔:你总是以"我对你很失望"开头.
Carol: Well usually you start with "I'm so disappointed in you".
杰森:开萝尔.
Jason: Carol.
本:然后你说……迈克,你不能考得再好一点吗?
Ben: And then you say...Mike, aren't you capable of a lot more?"
麦琪:本.
Maggie: Ben.
迈克:哦,伙计们.你们这个样子,好像我考了不及格,我通过了.
Mike: Oh come on guys.You are acting like I failed or something.I got by.
杰森:迈克,通过了并不值得骄傲,
Jason: Ah Mike.Getting by isn't anything to be proud of.
难道就这样一直混到老吗?
Isn't getting by getting old?
迈克:爸爸,你说你不会难过的.
Mike: Dad, you said you weren't going to get upset.
杰森:我撒了谎.
Jason: I lied.
麦琪:迈克,我们在考虑你的未来.
Maggie: Mike, we are concerned about your future.
杰森:迟早在未来选择你之前,你得选择你的未来.
Jason: Sooner or later you got to pick your future before it picks you.
迈克:我仍然想成为一个演员,
Mike: Look, I'm still thinking about becoming an actor you know.
你们知道的.我是说如果罗伯特……德尼罗带上这样的成绩回家,
I mean, I doubt that Robert De Niro's parents would have hassled him if
他的父母肯定不会和他吵.
he brought home those grades.
杰森:我敢说如果德尼罗在演学生时,他的成绩肯定是全A.
Jason: Well I bet if De Niro were playing a student, he's be getting all A's.
迈克:如果他扮演我的话就不会.我想说,
Mike: Not if he were playing me.I mean come on guys.
伙计们,我很感谢你们想着我,
I appreciate you thinking about me and everything but look.
但是,听着,
I am a college student who is passing all his courses,
我是一个通过了所有课程的大学生,有一辆体面的小汽车,
has a decent car and his own apartment.
还有自己的房间,我得说通过已经很好了.
I would say that getting by has done me AOK.
哦,我还有你们的爱和支持.
Oh, and plus, I have the love and support of my family.
麦琪:别狡辩,迈克.
Maggie: Don't push it Mike.
波纳:迈克,迈克,
Boner: Mikey, Mikey, big news!Oh, hello everybody.
重大消息!哦,大家好,
I was just going to tell Mikey, but seen as it's your kitchen,
我要来告诉迈克,你们也可以听.
I guess you can hear it too.
迈克:你没事吧,波纳?
Mike: You alright Bone?
波纳:是的,不能再好了.在这等着.
Boner: Yeah, never better.Now wait here.
开萝尔:别做傻事,波纳,我们在吃饭.
Carol: Don't do anything gross Boner.We are eating.
波纳:从蒙台梭利到的黎波里,
Boner: From the holes of Montessori, to the shores of Tripoli.
你怎么想呢?
What do you think?
迈克:我想他的主发动机已经熄火了.
Mike: I think his main engine just went down.
本:你从哪儿得到这个帽子的?
Ben: Where did you get the neat hat?
波纳:今天下午两点,中部时间一点,
Boner: As of two pm this afternoon, one pm central, it is official.
那是官方时间,我成了一名海军陆战队员,我想你知道这个消息会大吃一惊的.
I am a Marine.I see you are speechless from the heavyosity of my news.
迈克:你做了什么?
Mike: You did what?
波纳:我参加陆战队了?
Boner: I enlisted in the Marines.
迈克:哪家?
Mike: Whose?
波纳:我没有问,我希望是我们的.
Boner: Well I didn't ask.Ours I hope.
迈克:波纳,你是不是疯了?
Mike: Boner, are you out of your mind?
波纳:我看起来像疯了吗?
Boner: Do I look like I am out of my mind?
麦琪:别插嘴,本.
Maggie: Not one word Ben.
波纳:听着,我要回家告诉父母,路过你家,我忍不住想来告诉你,让你分享我的快乐.说完了.
Boner: Now listen.I got to go home and tell my parents about this.Yours
was on my way home and I couldn't resist coming in and sharing my joy
Nough said
迈克:不,波纳.我还没说呢.
Mike: No Boner.That is not nearly nough said.
波纳:哦,我忘了.
Boner: Oh, I forgot.As you were.
(波纳家)
(At Boner house)
波纳:嘿,迈克.我关了它.
Boner: Hey Mikey.Let me turn this off.
邻居:谢天谢地.
Neighbors: Finally.
迈克:嘿,波纳,我们说一下陆战队的事吧,好吗?
Mike: Hey Bone.Let's talk about this Marine thing.Alright.
波纳:好的,迈克,我一直想和你谈.
Boner: Sure Mike.I've been wanting to talk to you.
迈克:你所说的加入陆战队的事,是不是和你说的你和安吉拉?
Mike: Now what you said about joining the Marines isn't like what you
斯科芬格里奥的事性质一样呢?
said about what you and Angela Scoffengelio did?
波纳:不,不不.陆战队的事是真的.
Boner: No, no, no, no.The Marine thing is true.
迈克:哦,不.
Mike: Oh no.
波纳:什么?
Boner: What?
迈克:也许还有希望.你签字了吗?
Mike: Well maybe there's still hope.You didn't sign anything did you?
波纳:是的,我的名字.
Boner: Well my name.
迈克:哦,不.
Mike: Oh no.
波纳:我还参加了考试.
Boner: And I took a test.
迈克:你参加了测试,很好,你肯定被淘汰了.
Mike: That you probably had to pass.Alright, you are out of this deal.
波纳:我通过了.
Boner: I passed.
迈克:你通过了!波纳,
Mike: You passed!Boner,
你就是要挑这样的时间来通过测试吗?
did you have to pick a time like this to pass a test?
波纳:是的,两星期以后我就要去美丽的,阳光灿烂的圣地亚哥.
Boner: Yep.And in two weeks I leave for basic and beautiful sunny San Diego.
迈克:哦,波纳,
Mike: Oh Bone.Why didn't you jut think before you ran off and did some
在你跑出去做这些疯狂的事之前你为什么不想想?
crazy thing like this?
波纳:迈克我一直在考虑这个,很久了.
Boner: Well Mikey I have been thinking about this.For a long time.
当我今天拿到成绩单时我就意识到我要做什么.
And when I got my grades today I realized what I had to do.
迈克:波纳,你在有这些疯狂的念头的时候,
Mike: Well Boner why didn't you just tell me that you were having these
你为什么不告诉我呢?
crazy thoughts.
波纳:我想过,但是我想你会不爱听.
Boner: Well I was going to, but figured you didn't want to hear about it.
还是从头说吧,当我……
See it all started when I was...
迈克:我不想听这个.
Mike: I don't want to hear about it.
你知道你干了一些什么吗?那可是海军陆战队.
Do you have any idea what you are doing?I mean this is the marines.
这些家伙们天不亮就要起床,
These are the guys who wake up when it's dark and run for six miles.
跑上六英里,
I mean they also carry guns.
而且他们还扛着枪.你真的想加入这样一个组织,
Do you really want to join an organization that's going to trust you with
用一只装满子弹的枪信任你?
a loaded gun?
波纳:迈克,我要去的地方没有枪,我挑了炮兵.
Boner: Mikey, I aint going to be anywhere near guns.I signed up for artillery.
迈克:那你就更傻了.
Mike: I mean this is stupid even for you.
波纳:我本期望你会因此对我好一点,
Boner: You know I expected you to be a little nicer to me about this.
你是我最好的朋友.
You're supposed to be my best friend.
迈克:波纳,我是你最好的朋友.
Mike: Bone I am your best friend.
所以我要告诉你,
That's why I am telling you if you join the Marines you are throwing your
如果你加入陆战队,这会毁了你的一生.
life away
波纳:迈克,我没有参加陆军,
Boner: Mikey, I didn't just join the army or the navy or the National Guard.
海军或者国民警卫队,我参加了陆战队.
I joined the Marines.
迈克:从你光屁股那会我就知道你是个疯子.
Mike: I should have known you were nuts the first day you showed up without
your pants.
波纳:哦?
Boner: Hu?
迈克:一年级的时候,
Mike: In the first grade.
你只穿着内衣和罩衣上学.
When you showed up in your over coat and your underwear.
波纳:我穿了裤子,那天我妈妈给我穿的,
Boner: I didn't forget my pants.My mum dressed me that day.
我告诉你一百次了.
I told you that a hundred times.
迈克:来,会有办法让你退出的,
Mike: Come on, there's got to be a way to get you out of this somehow.
我有了.我爸爸是精神病学家,
I got it.My dads a psychiatrist, he's always saying how you're nuts.
他总是说你们这些疯子.我们就让他开个证明.
We'll just get him to write it down.
波纳:迈克,我不想退出.
Boner: Mikey I don't want to get out of this.
迈克:来,波纳,你不能让一张糟糕的成绩单吓倒.
Mike: Come on Bone, you can't let a bad report card spook you like this.
波纳:你说起来很容易,你得了D.
Boner: It's easy for you to say.You got D's.
迈克:好了,你的未来呢?
Mike: Alright, what about your future?
波纳:迈克,除非我加入陆战队,
Boner: Mikey, until I joined the marines, I didn't have a future.
否则我不会有未来.八个星期后,我就可以驾驶三千万美元的坦克了.
In eight weeks I could be driving a thirty million dollar tank.
迈克:波纳,我甚至教不会你换档!
Mike: Boner, I couldn't even teach you a stick shift!
听着,我要告诉你,如果你加入了陆战队,
Now look, I'm telling you, if you join the Marines,
你会遗憾一生,你父母怎么说?
you are just going to upset your whole life.What did your parents say?
波纳:他们哭了?
Boner: They cried.
迈克:看看.
Mike: See.
波纳:他们说他们从来没有这么为我自豪过.我的爸爸是个陆战队员,
Boner: They said they'd never been prouder of me.You know my dad was a Marine.
他说那才使他有了今天.
He said that's what's made him what he is today.
波纳爸爸:该去睡觉了,士兵波纳.
Boner's Dad: Time to hit the wrap, Private Stabone.
波纳妈妈:睡吧,我的小陆战队员.
Boner's Mum: Bedtime my little Marine.
波纳:我可以再待几分钟吗?我在和迈克说话.
Boner: Can I stay a couple more minutes?Me and Mikey are talking.
波纳爸爸:当然可以.
Boner's Dad: Sure, a couple of minutes will be fie.
波纳妈妈:今晚过得怎样,迈克?
Boner's mum: And how are you tonight Mikey?
迈克:我很好,你们怎么样?
Mike: Oh I'm fine.And how are you guys?
波纳爸爸:太好了,
Boner's dad: Damn fine Mikey.
迈克.我们为理查德的决定感到非常的开心,
We are just so tickled pink about Richards's decision.Mrs.
波纳太太都哭得眼泪哗哗的.
Stabone actually wept in her linguini.
迈克:喔.
Mike: Wo.
波纳妈妈:他不在身边当然会难过,
Boner's Mum: It will be hard not having him around,
但是他做得很棒,对他自己,
but what a wonderful thing he's doing,
对我们感恩的国家.
for himself and for our grateful nation.
波纳爸爸:嘿,嘿嘿,我们等着你,理查德.
Boner's Dad: hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.We'll wait for you inside Richard.
波纳:好的.
Boner: Yeah.
波纳妈妈:晚安,迈克.
Boner's Mum: Goodnight Mikey.
迈克:晚安.
Mike: Goodnight.
波纳爸爸:晚安,西维尔.
Boner's dad: Goodnight Seaver.
迈克:嘿(父母大叫).
Mike: Hey.(Parents go in crying) Boy.
波纳:是的,他们终于平静下来了.
Boner: Yeah.They are finally calming down.
迈克:他们比你还疯狂.
Mike: Man, they are nuttier than you are.
波纳:嘿,迈克.这样说很粗鲁.
Boner: Hey Mike.That's a very rude thing to say.
迈克:粗鲁!看看你是怎么对我的!
Mike: Rude!Compared to what you are doing to me.
波纳:我怎么了?
Boner: What am I doing to you?
迈克:波纳,听着.
Mike: Boner look.How do you think that I am supposed to get through the
你怎么想让我一个人熬到大学毕业?你拆开了我们这个伟大的团队.
rest of school by myself?Hu?I mean you are splitting up a great team here.
我得D,你得F.
Me with the D's and you with the F's.
波纳:迈克,我很抱歉,但是……
Boner: Mike I'm sorry but...
迈克:你以为你说句对不起就能解决所有问题吗?
Mike: And you think you can say you're sorry and make everything alright?
波纳:至少在未来选择我之前我选择了未来.我很难过,
Boner: At least I'm picking my future before I let it pick me.
厌倦了得过且过,迈克.我知道我想做什么.
I'm sick and tired of just getting by Mikey.I know what I want to do.
迈克:真没想过你会同意我的爸爸.但是很好,
Mike: I never thought I'd hear the day when you agree with my father.
很好!
But fine, fine fine!
理好头发,找那些匍匐前进的家伙去吧.
Shave your head and hang around with guy who crawl around on their bellies.
波纳:你知道我做了关系一生的决定,我最好的朋友却骂我.
Boner: You know I make one decision in my whole life and my best friend
这是我第一次知道自己想做什么,知道自己要去哪?
dumps on me.For the first time in my life I know what I want to
再见了,我要回家了.
do and I know where I'm going.So to heck with you, I'm going home.
迈克:波纳,你住在这儿.
Mike: Boner, you live here.
波纳:别把你的想法强加于我,迈克?西维尔.
Boner: Don't you run your mind games on me Michael Seaver.
迈克:波纳,你为什么没和我谈?
Mike: Look Bone, why didn't you just to me about this.
波纳:我试过了.
Boner: I tried to.
迈克:很明显还不够.
Mike: Well obviously not hard enough.
波纳:迈克,我要离开了,
Boner: You know Mikey, just cos I'm going away,
不过这不意味着我们不能成为朋友了.
it doesn't mean that we have to stop being friends.
迈克:那意味着什么呢?
Mike: Yeah well what does it mean?
波纳爸爸:理查德!和迈克说再见吧.
Boner's Dad: Richard!Time to say goodbye to Mikey.
迈克:那就是意味着再见.
Mike: That's exactly what it means.
杰森:哟!我以为是个笨拙的小偷呢.
Jason: Phew!I thought for a minute that it was a clumsy burglar.
迈克:波纳真的参加陆战队了.你能相信吗,爸爸?
Mike: I mean Boner actually joined the Marines.Can you believe that dad?
杰森:喔
Jason: Well...
迈克:是的,这个卑鄙小人两星期后要去参加军训了.
Mike: Yeah.That dweeb leaves for basic and training in two weeks.
杰森:为什么,你为什么要生气呢?
Jason: Why, what are you so angry about?
迈克:你没听见我说的吗?他刚刚加入了陆战队.
Mike: Haven't you heard a word I said dad?He just joined the Marines.
杰森:那也应该是陆战队感到不安啊?来,
Jason: Well shouldn't it be the Marines who are upset?Come on Mike.
迈克.
I mean I understand you being upset about your best friend going away,
我理解你这么难过是因为你最好的朋友要离开了,但是你所有的愤怒是从何而来呢?
but where is all this anger from?
迈克:因为,爸爸,
Mike: Because dad, he's making a big mistake.
他犯了一个大错误.你应当听见他今晚所说的了.
I mean you should have heard him tonight.I was pathetic.
我很可怜,他不停地唠叨,关于这个决定,
He was babbling some nonsense about making a decision about what he wants
关于他想决定自己的命运.在未来选择他之前选择他的未来.
to do with his life.About picking his future before it picks him.
杰森:说说可怜的地方,迈克.
Jason: Get to the pathetic part Mike.
麦琪:我听见吵闹声,你这个时候在做什么呢,迈克?
Maggie: I heard all the yelling.What did you do this time Mike?
杰森:波纳真的入伍了.
Jason: Boner really enlisted.
麦琪:真的?
Maggie: Really?
迈克:是的,我想和他谈谈,但他不听我.
Mike: Yeah.I mean I tried to talk to him but he wouldn't listen to me.
我是说,像这种谈话,
I mean do you have any idea what its like to talk to somebody about their
关系到他的未来,他却一个字也不听,你们能有什么办法吗?
future, and have not a word of what you're saying sink in?
杰森:不不,不是我.麦琪你怎么样?
Jason: No.No.Not me.How about you Mags?
麦琪:无能为力.
Maggie: Nah.
杰森:迈克,
Jason: Mike, have you considered the possibility that Boner's decision
你考虑过波纳的决定可能对他是一个好的选择吗?
is a good one for him?
迈克:哦,爸爸.
Mike: Oh come on dad.Boner's a quitter.He's a college drop out.
波纳是个胆小鬼,他是大学的逃兵,你还要护着他?
And you defend him?
麦琪:迈克,你为什么如此生气?
Maggie: Mike, why are you so angry?
迈克:你们俩怎么了?呃?
Mike: What is with the two of you?Hu?I mean isn't it obvious?
我的意思还不明显吗?波纳要离开我,
Boner is leaving me and he's happy about it.
他倒很开心.
And now he's going off raving about how great it is to have found his
他以为他找到了他愚蠢的将来,他以为他做得很了不起.
stupid future.
麦琪:找到自己的未来不是一件快事.
Maggie: Finding your future is not a bad thing.
迈克:哦,那么你也想让我加入陆战队吗?
Mike: Oh, so do you want me to go and join the Marines too?
麦琪:不,但是考虑你的将来不会对你有坏处.
Maggie: No.But it wouldn't hurt you to think about your future.
迈克:你们好像认为波纳比我强.
Mike: You're acting like Boner's got the jump on me, or something.
杰森:你认为呢?
Jason: You think he does?
迈克:波纳!哦!白日做梦.
Mike: Boner!Hu!That will be the day.As you were.
麦琪:波纳,陆战队
Maggie: Boner.Marine.
杰森:这些小孩子什么时候长成大人了,麦琪?
Jason: When did these kids become adults Maggie?
麦琪:我不知道.
Maggie: I don't know.
对于我来说,波纳总是那个一年级的小孩子,
To me Boner will always be that little kid in the first grade,
忘记了穿裤子而哭哭啼啼.
crying because he forgot his pants.
杰森:是的,很快他就会保护我们的国家.上帝保佑美国.
Jason: Yeah.Soon he'll be defending our country.God bless America.
杰森:今晚早上在哪个车站送你们?
Jason: So, where's the station sending you this morning?
麦琪:我不知道,分配的人说会是个惊喜.
Maggie: I don't know.The assignment desk said it was a surprise.
开萝尔:你听起来不开心.
Carol: You don't sound happy.
麦琪:惊喜通常指一些奇怪的事.
Maggie: Well usually a surprise means something strange.
波纳:惊喜!
Boner: Surprise!
杰森:早上好!
Jason: Morning!
麦琪:看你.
Maggie: Look at you.
波纳:好的,军装很适合我,那是我爸爸的制服.
Boner: Yeah.Greens my color, aint it?It's my dad's uniform.
看,名字相同,所有都相同.
See, same name and everything.
杰森:太令人惊讶了.
Jason: Amazing.
波纳:是的.今天是我要去参加军训的日子,
Boner: Yeah.Well today's the day I leave for basic.
我爸爸在外面的车里,
My days out in the car waiting to take me to the airport and I just
等着送我去机场,我只是想在走之前打声招呼.
wanted to stop by before I left to say hey.Hey.
杰森:哦,你想的真是非常周到,波纳.
Jason: Oh that's very thoughtful of you Boner.
波纳:是的,你和西维尔太太就像是我的第二个父母.
Boner: Yeah, well you and Mrs.Seaver have been like second parents to me.
麦琪:哦,波纳,你嘴真甜.
Maggie: Oh Boner, that's so sweet.
波纳:还有你本,你就像我的第二个弟弟,
Boner: And you Bennie.You've been like a second brother to me.
尽管我并没有第一个.
Except I never had a first brother.
本:我想我要说声谢谢你.
Ben: Thanks I guess.
波纳:还有开萝尔,不要为这哭泣.
Boner: And Carol, well, why cry over what may have been.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
波纳:我知道我们相处得很棒,但是我相信你还会找到其他人的,
Boner: I know we would have been great together,
会有那一天.
but I'm sure you'll find somebody else.Someday.
开萝尔:谢谢你,我希望如此.
Carol: Thank you.I sure hope so.
波纳:所以,不管怎样.
Boner: So, anyway.
杰森:好的,你已经对迈克说再见了吗?
Jason: Yeah, have you already been up to say goodbye to Mike?
波纳:哦,不.我和迈克再也不说话了,我们发生了争吵.
Boner: Uh no.Me and Mike aint talking.We had a fight.
麦琪:哦,波纳,
Maggie: Oh Boner, if people stop talking to people they care about just
如果人们因为一场争吵就不再说话的话……
because of a fight...
本:屋子就更安静了.
Ben: This house would be a lot quieter.
麦琪:那倒是真的.
Maggie: That's true.
波纳:是的,我不想见迈克,
Boner: Yeah well, well, I don't want to see Mike.
我甚至不想和他说话.他在家吗?
I don't even want to talk to him.Is he home?
杰森:是的,他应该在.他可能睡着了.
Jason: Yeah he should be.He's probably asleep.
波纳:你怎么知道?
Boner: How do you now?
杰森:他十五分钟以后有堂课.
Jason: He's got a class in fifteen minutes.
迈克:钥匙呢.好的,波纳.
Mike: Keys.Alright.Boner.
波纳:迈克.
Boner: Mikey.
波纳:你要去上课吗?
Boner: So, are you on your way to class?
迈克:今天星期几?
Mike: What day is it today?
波纳:星期三.
Boner: Wednesday.
迈克:你说的对,我有课.
Mike: Oh, you're right.I do have a class.
波纳:我不想打扰你,我只是想说声再见,
Boner: I didn't want to bother you.I just want to say goodbye.
我今天要走了.
I'm leaving today.
迈克:好的,我知道.我正要去你家.
Mike: Yeah, I know.I was going to come by your house.
波纳:真的?
Boner: Yeah?
迈克:真的,我不能让我的好伙伴就这么走,
Mike: Yeah.I mean, hey.
一句招呼也不打.
I couldn't let my buddy leave without at least saying hey.Hey.
波纳:嘿.
Boner: Hey.
迈克:嘿,我以为你到了军营才会有衣服发.
Mike: Hey, you know I didn't think you'd get that suit till after boot camp.
波纳:哦,这是我爸爸的,他在塔姆得到的.
Boner: Oh, this is my dads.He got it in tam.
迈克:你不是指偷吧?
Mike: Don't you mean Nam?
波纳:不不,塔姆就是塔姆波特.
Boner: No, no, no.Tam as in Tampot.That's where he was stationed.
那是他服役的地方,那是他最喜欢的玩笑.
That's his favorite joke.
迈克:很有趣.
Mike: It's a good one.
波纳:好的,现在我想让其他陆战队员知道士兵理查德?
Boner: Yeah.Now I want to show the other Marines that Private Richard
波纳已经准备好了.你知道座右铭"时刻准备着",很高兴看见你,
Stabone is ready.You know the motto "Be prepared".
不再争吵了,迈克.
You know it's nice to see you and not be arguing Mike.
迈克:是的,是的,
Mike: Yeah.Yeah you know, I've been thinking Bone and you know,
我一直在想,波纳,如果你很严肃地对待这件愚蠢的事
if you are really this serious about this dumb thing...
波纳:那不是一件愚蠢的事.
Boner: It's not a dumb thing.
迈克:嘿,听着,
Mike: Hey.Look, let's not go through that again.
我们别再争吵了.你是我的朋友,我想对你说再见.
You're my friend and I want to ay goodbye.
波纳:好的,再见.
Boner: Fine.Goodbye.
迈克:波纳,我很难过.
Mike: Look Boner.I'm sorry.
波纳:我也是,迈克.我想我们后会有期.
Boner: Me too Mikey.Well, I guess I'll see you later.
迈克:是的,后会有期.
Mike: Yeah.I'll see you later.
波纳:那是我的爸爸,我走了.
Boner: It's my dad.Got to go.
迈克:嘿,我送你下楼.
Mike: Hey, well I'll, I'll walk you down the stairs.
上两个星期你做了什么?
So what've you been doing the last couple of weeks?
波纳:我一直在准备,
Boner: Well I've been getting ready,
每天起床跑六英里.
you know working out and running those six miles everyday.
迈克:哦.
Mike: Yeah.
波纳:问题是我太累了,总是得乘车回来.
Boner: Thing is I get so tired, I usually need a ride back.
迈克:你为什么不只跑三英里呢,然后……很棒,跑步很棒.
Mike: Why don't you just run three miles one way and then...well good.Running's good.
波纳:整件事情我感觉非常好.
Boner: I feel so great about this whole thing.
迈克:是的,你不紧张了?
Mike: Yeah.You're not nervous?
波纳:我人生中第一次感觉到明天就要不同了,更好,最好.我再也不是那个波纳了.我要成为士兵理查德?波纳.
Boner: No.For the first time in my whole life I feel that tomorrow is
going to be different.Better.The best.I'm not going to just be Boner anymore
I'm going to be Private Richard Stabone
迈克:是的,波纳,我认为你做得对.
Mike: Yeah well, you know Boner, I think you are doing the right thing.
波纳:谢谢,迈克,我也是.
Boner: Thanks Mikey.Me too.
迈克:嘿,你会写信给我吗?
Mike: Hey, you're going to write me?
波纳:哦,当然,你住在哪?
Boner: Oh sure.Where do you live?
迈克:就是这儿.
Mike: Right here.
波纳:不,我是说你的地址.
Boner: No, I mean your address.
迈克:罗宾汉街15号,你知道的.
Mike: Fifteen Robinhood Lane.You know that.
波纳:嘿,这可是十三年没写信给你了.
Boner: Hey, it's been thirteen years and I never had to write you.
迈克:是的,你可以直接上门.
Mike: Yeah.You could just come by.
波纳:军训要两个月,结束后我会有三天的休假.
Boner: Well basics is over in two months, and then I get a three day furlough.
迈克:太好了,我都等不及了.
Mike: Alright, I can't wait.
波纳:好的,我们可以保持友谊,
Boner: Yeah, we can hang out and goof around.
把时间花在你身上,我很开心.
I'll be happy to waste time with you then.
迈克:哦.
Mike: Ah yeah.
波纳:像以前那样.
Boner: Like the good old days.
迈克:你发誓.
Mike: You bet ya.
波纳:好的,棍子也不可能打折我们的友谊.
Boner: Yeah, you can't kill a friendship like ours with a stick.
迈克:即使是一根大棍子也不能.
Mike: Not even with a big stick.
波纳:不能.
Boner: No.
迈克:我们后会有期.
Mike: Well I guess I'll see you later.
波纳:是的,后会有期.我要送你到台阶.
Boner: Yeah.See you later.I'll walk you back to your steps.
迈克:好的,太好了.
Mike: Alright.Great.
波纳:是的.后会有期.
Boner: Yeah.So.See you later.
迈克:嘿,我要送你到车道.
Mike: Hey, I'll walk you halfway down the driveway.
波纳爸爸:我们走吧,我的小军官.
Boner's dad: Let's go, you little jarhead.
波纳:我得走了,我听见陆战队员慢慢得在皱眉.
Boner: I'd better go.I hear the Marines frown on tardiness.
迈克:祝你好运,波纳.
Mike: Good luck.Bone.
波纳:你也是,迈克.
Boner: You too.Mikey.
迈克:嘿,波纳,
Mike: Hey Bone, you know how the marines say that they are looking for
你知道陆战队在征兵时怎么说吗?
a few good men?
波纳:知道.
Boner: Yeah.
迈克:现在他们漏了一个好小伙.
Mike: Well now they got one less good man to look for.
波纳:罗宾汉街17号.我知道了.
Boner: Fifteen Robinhood Lane.Got it.
迈克:好的,我知道你记得了,波纳,揍死他们.
Mike: Yeah, I know you do Bone.Knock em dead.
波纳:不是在军训,那只是锻炼.
Boner: Not at boot camp.We only practice.
迈克:你知道我的意思.
Mike: You know what I mean.
波纳:是的.
Boner: Yeah.
(迈克的脑中回响起杰森的声音):迟早在未来选择你之前,
Jason's voice in Mike's head): Sooner or later you have to pick your future,
(你得选择你的未来.
before it picks you.
(迈克的脑中回响起波纳的声音):嘿,在未来选择我之前,我正在选择我的未来.
迈克:是时候了,迈克,是时候了.
00:23:21,900
(Boner's voice in Mike's head): Hey, I'm picking my future before it picks me. Mike: It's time Mike.It's time.